Guide to the Stanford University, Libraries, Staff Association, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Libraries, Staff Association, records
1942-2001
SC0314
Stanford University. Libraries. Staff Association..
9 Linear feet
These records date from 1942 to 2001 and include correspondence, minutes, financial records, newsletters, surveys, and other materials.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: early records are in remote storage and paging those boxes can take up to 5 days.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The organization of Stanford library staff has been known by several names: SULA [Stanford University Librarians Assembly], SULSA [Stanford University Libraries Staff Association], LASU [Library Association of Stanford University], and SLSA [Stanford Libraries Staff Association]. At one time there were separate groups for professional staff and support staff, but that distinction was later dropped. In addition to addressing professional concerns and issues, the association also sponsored events and held book sales.
Description of the Collection
These records date from 1942 to 2001 and include correspondence, minutes, financial records, newsletters, surveys, and other materials.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Libraries--Employees.; Stanford University. Libraries. Librarians Assembly.; Stanford University. Libraries. Staff Association..; Academic libraries--Employees.
Collection Contents
- Early Records
  Note: these early records are in remote storage and can take 5 days to retrieve.
  - Box 86 of the original SC 112 collection contains the following SULA materials:
    - Correspondence (Box 86)
    - Meetings: 1947-1950 (Box 86)
    - Meetings: 1951-1955 (Box 86)
    - Meetings: 1959-60 (Box 86)
    - Staff Survey 1965 (Box 86)
    - Constitution (Box 86)
    - Sandstone Scribe, 1952-1952 (Box 86)
    - Financial Reports (Box 86)
    - Coffee (Box 86)
    - Christmas party, 1959-1960 (Box 86)
    - History (Box 86)
    - Membership (Box 86)
    - Staff Room 1959 (Box 86)
    - Salary Survey, 1958 (Box 86)
    - Notices (Box 86)
    - Orientation (Box 86)
  - Box 93 of the original SC 112 collection contains the following folders:
    - SULA programming, Membership Committees, 1975-1976 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - SULA Professional concerns, 1975-76 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - SULA 1975-76 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - SULA 1976-77 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Box 87 of the original SC 112 collection contains the following SULSA materials:
    - Sandstone and Scribe, 1942-1951 (vol. 1-4) (Box 87)
    - Sandstone and Scribe, 1948-1954 (Box 87)
    - Christmas Music, December 1956 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1957-58 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1961 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1962 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1963 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1964 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1965 (Box 87)
    - Miscellany, 1965-66 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1967-68 (Box 87)
    - General, 1967-68 (Constitution Policy) (Box 87)
    - General, 1967-68 (Executive Comm. Gen. Mtg.) (Box 87)
    - General, 1967-68 (Staff Room, Scholarship) (Box 87)
    - General, 1967-68 (Orientation, Special Events (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1969 (Box 87)
    - General, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1970 (Box 87)
    - General Records, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Executive Board records, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Orientation, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Orientation, tours, 1970-74 (Box 87)
    - Petition on Health, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Public Service Committee, Annual report/minutes, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Public Service Committee, General records, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Public Service Committee, Users privileges/serials, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Public Service Committee, Reference statistics/projects, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1971 (Box 87)
    - Picnic, 1971 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1972 (Box 87)
    - Annual Reports 1972 (Box 87)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1972 (Box 87)
    - Personnel Committee, 1972 (Box 87)
    - Other Committees, 1972 (Box 87)
    - Program Committee, 1972 (Box 87)
    - Staff Survey (Box 87)
    - Program Committee, 1973 (Box 87)
    - Treasurer's receipts, 1973 (Box 87)
    - Safety Committee, 1974 (Box 87)
    - Scholarship Application, 1974 (Box 87)
    - Staff Development Committee, 1974 (Box 87)
    - Treasurer's Receipts, 1974 (Box 87)
    - General Records, 1975 (Box 87)
    - Search Committee for Personnel Officer, 1975 (Box 87)
    - Treasurer's Receipts, 1975 (Box 87)
    - General Records, 1976 (Box 87)
    - Treasurer's Receipts, 1976 (Box 87)
    - Executive Council Meetings, 1077 (Box 87)
    - Orientation 1977 (Box 87)
    - Program Committee 1977 (Box 87)
    - SULSA Questionnaire, 1977 (Box 87)
  - Box 88 of the original SC 112 collection contains the following SULSA materials:
    - Social Concerns Committee, 1977 (Box 88)
    - Treasurer's Receipts, 1977 (Box 88)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 88)
    - Executive Council Meetings, 1978 (Box 88)
    - Financial Statements, 1978 (Box 88)
    - Membership, 1978 (1977) (Box 88)
    - Personnel Committee, 1978 (1977) (Box 88)
    - Posters and Announcements, 1978 (Box 88)
    - Program Committee, 1978 (Box 88)
    - SULSA Questionnaires, 1978 (Box 88)
    - Resource Sharing – IG-R (Box 88)
    - Staff Room, 1978 (1977) (Box 88)
    - Treasurer's Receipts, 1978 (Box 88)
    - SULSA Constitution (as amended through 1965) (Box 88)
    - Information Handbook (1968) (Box 88)
  - Box 228 of the original SC 112 collection contains the following SULSA materials:
    - Miscellaneous projects – SULSA 1980 (Box 228, Folder 1)
    - Minutes – SULSA 1980 (Box 228, Folder 2)
    - Personal concerns committee (Box 228, Folder 3)
    - Constitution and bylaws (Box 228, Folder 4)
    - SULSA Questionnaires (Box 228, Folder 5)
    - Committee Work 1980 (Box 228, Folder 6)
    - SULSA 1979 (Box 228, Folder 7)
    - Nominating committee 1979 (Box 228, Folder 8)
    - Personnel committee (Box 228, Folder 9)
    - Personnel (Box 228, Folder 10)
    - Task Force in Supervisor Evaluations (Box 228, Folder 11)
    - Personnel Committee (Box 228, Folder 12)
    - Personnel Committee - materials (Box 228, Folder 13)
    - Social Committee 1980 (Box 228, Folder 14)
    - Member responses (Box 228, Folder 15)
    - SULSA workshop (Box 228, Folder 16)
    - Photocopy receipts 1981 (Box 228, Folder 17)
    - SULSA (Box 228, Folder 18)
    - Staff Survey (Box 228, Folder 19)
    - West Wing renovation (Box 228, Folder 20)
    - ALA Orientation program (Box 228, Folder 21)
    - SULSA 1981 (Box 228, Folder 22)
    - SULSA personnel committee (Box 228, Folder 23)
    - Parking (Box 228, Folder 24)
    - Parking (Box 228, Folder 25)
    - SULSA Personnel committee (Box 228, Folder 26)
    - SULSA PCC 1981-82 (Box 228, Folder 27)
    - SULSA PCC 1982-83 (Box 228, Folder 28)
    - SULSA-SULA Booksale 1982 (Box 228, Folder 29)
    - SULSA (Box 228, Folder 30)
    - SULSA Executive Council (Box 228, Folder 31)
    - H and S committee (Box 228, Folder 32)
    - SULSA minutes 1982-83 (Box 228, Folder 33)
    - Parking survey (Box 228, Folder 34)
    - Staff recognition - summer 1983 responses (Box 228, Folder 35)
    - SULSA-SULA Booksale (Box 228, Folder 36)
    - SULSA Executive board meetings (Box 228, Folder 37)
    - SULSA 1984-85 (Box 228, Folder 38)
    - Merit Zone (Box 228, Folder 39)
    - Staff recognition (Box 228, Folder 40)
  - Box 229 of the original SC 112 collection contains the following SULSA materials:
    - SULSA Personnel Committee (Box 229, Folder 1)
    - Personnel Committee, Staff Association (Box 229, Folder 2)
    - Personnel Committee, Staff Association (Box 229, Folder 3)
    - Personnel Committee, Staff Development Committee (Box 229, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous 1982 (Box 229, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous 1982 (Box 229, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous 1982 (Box 229, Folder 7)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1990-171
  - ALA Library Tour (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ALA Library Tour: Participants A-E (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ALA Library Tour: Participants F-L (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ALA Library Tour: Participants M-R (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ALA Library Tour: Participants S-Z (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Academic Council Committee, 1983/84 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Academic Staff Handbook: grievance procedure (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sally Buchanon File, 1984-85 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bylaws (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising Committee, 1984/85-1986/87 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - David R. McDonald file, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Membership Committee (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - PCC: Annual reports (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - PCC: Memoranda and miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - PCC: Minutes, Jan. 13, 1981-May 13, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - PCC: Minutes, Jan. 2, 1979-Dec. 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - PCC: Minutes, Jan. 23, 1978-Dec. 14, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - PCC: Projects, 1979-81 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - PCC: Projects, 1967-78 and undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Program Committee, 1983/84-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ULC [University Library Committee], 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ULC, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: SULA, 1987-88 (Box 3)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1991-055
  - SULSA Minutes, Dec. 1976, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - SULSA Staff lounge renovation correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - SULSA Membership list, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SULSA Minutes, correspondence, handouts, revision of constitution, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SULSA Minutes, correspondence, handouts, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SULSA Minutes, correspondence, handouts, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - SULSA Minutes 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - SULSA Correspondence and handouts 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - SULSA Minutes 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SULSA Minutes, correspondence, handouts, membership list, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SULSA Minutes, correspondence, treasurer's reports, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - SULSA General, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SULSA 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SULSA 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - SULSA 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - SULSA Board, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2000-133
  - Continuing appointment data, 6/88 – 11/88 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Professional Concerns Committee, 12/86 – 2/87 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Professional Concerns Committee, 9/88 – 9/90 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Professional Concerns Committee, 11/87 – 6/88 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Professional Concerns Committee, grievance procedures, July 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Professional Concerns Committee, Richard Aroksaar, Apr. – June, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Professional Concerns Committee, benefits for librarians, Mar. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Professional Concerns Committee, oral history / SU librarians, n.d (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alleged committee on academic staff affairs, May 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Club membership, 11/80 – 8/82 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Continuing appointment program, 3/89 – 10/89 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Child Care Centers: SU, Jan. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Staff Housing Dec. 1980 – Mar. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campus staff housing, Jan. 1981 – Apr. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lyman Award, 1985-89 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Armenian bibliographies – Lyman award (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jim Adams – Lyman Award selection (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Katchadourian – Lyman Award (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Lyman Award 1983 – Jim Adams (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lyman Award – general, administrative (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lyman 1984 – H. Katchadourian (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lyman 1986 – Bill Chace (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lyman 1987 - Elsen (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Lyman 1988 – David Kennedy (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Lyman 1989 - Middlebrook (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - SULA Program Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Places (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Historical File (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - SULA Program Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - SULA Program Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - SULA Program Committee, 1982-1986 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - SULA Program Committee, 1982-1986 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - SULA Program Committee, 1982-1986 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - SULA Program Committee, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2002-296
  - Distinguished Service Awards binder, 1991-1997 (Box 1)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2006-298
  - Book Sale 1991-92 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Book Sale 1997-99 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Book Sale 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - By Laws [Library Association of Stanford University] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Event records, 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial records, 1995-96 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Financial records, 1996-97 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Financial records, 1996-98 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Financial records: account book1984-92 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial records: Credit Union statement of accounts (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Financial records: financial information (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Holiday Party, 1991-93 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ideas – potential to-do's 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - LASU records 1994-95 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting notes, event records, 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Older records, 1989-94 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SULA (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SULSA (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SULSA/SULA merger (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - SULSA Personnel Concerns Committee (1 of 2) 1983-88 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SULSA Personnel Concerns Committee (2 of 2) 1983-88 (Box 2, Folder 8)